<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Meet Gor - Tag: tmux</title>
    <link>https://meetgor.com</link>
    <description>Posts tagged with tmux</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:49:08 UTC</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Tmux scroll mode select and copy</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;I have found scrolling in tmux is a bit unconventional. Maybe its just me, but sometimes, the terminal interfaces are different, sometimes they are a bit wired, I use Ghostty right now, so selection without tmux works a charm, but the moment I am in tmux, ahmm, it kind of breaks.&#xA;&#xA;The selection of text doesn&#39;t work with the mouse atleast, so I thought, I need a keyboard centric selection and copying mechanism, and dug in this rabit hole. Turns out, tmux is way better in selection then zellij, the multiplexer I had been using due to scroll and selection issues in terminal interfaces.&#xA;&#xA;It&#39;s simple as `Prefix + [` to enter the scroll mode, `Shift+V` or `Ctrl+space` or `Ctrl+v` to start the selection in different ways, and finally, `Enter` or `Ctrl+j` to copy to clipboard. There is a dedicated mode for vi users, to feel at home. Tmux + Vim again a deadly combo.&#xA;&#xA;## Entering Scroll Mode&#xA;&#xA;To enter scroll mode, I had this config setup in my `.tmux.conf` file:&#xA;&#xA;```&#xA;set -g mouse on&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;However if you want to enter without mouse on, you can use:&#xA;&#xA;```&#xA;Ctrl + b + [&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;Here the `Ctrl + b` is for the prefix key, and `[` is the key for enterring into the  `Scroll Mode`&#xA;&#xA;From here on you can use `hjkl` or arrow keys to scroll up or down.&#xA;&#xA;To quit, you can press `q` or hit escape.&#xA;&#xA;## Selecting &#xA;&#xA;Right now in scrolling mode, you can only navigate to the next or previous line. &#xA;&#xA;But you can use `Ctrl + &lt;Space&gt;` to select any arbitrary sections of the terminal output.&#xA;There are two modes in tmux for this the `copy-mode` i.e. the default, and the `copy-mode-vi`.&#xA;&#xA;Without any config, this is be set to the default `copy-mode`, so we can use `Ctrl + Space` to begin selection in the scroll mode.&#xA;&#xA;To get more keybindings for the copy-mode and copy-mode-vi, use &#xA;&#xA;For copy-mode&#xA;```&#xA;tmux list-keys -T copy-mode&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;For copy-mode-vi&#xA;```&#xA;tmux list-keys -T copy-mode-vi&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;This is a default and can be over-written by using the following config:&#xA;&#xA;```&#xA;setw -g mode-keys vi&#xA;unbind-key -T copy-mode-vi Space&#xA;&#xA;# replace &lt;your-key&gt; with the key combination you want&#xA;bind-key -T copy-mode-vi &lt;your-key&gt; send-keys -X begin-selection&#xA;&#xA;# Example: using ctrl + b + v as the key to start selection&#xA;# bind-key -T copy-mode-vi v send-keys -X begin-selection&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;This all would be applied to copy-mode if you are not changing the keybindings for copy-mode-vi.&#xA;&#xA;## Copying&#xA;&#xA;Once, you have the selected region or piece of text, you can copy that to the clipboard (that is what you do, while logs-driven debugging :).&#xA;&#xA;By default, you can use:&#xA;&#xA;For copy-mode&#xA;- `Ctrl + w` &#xA;&#xA;or &#xA;&#xA;For copy-mode-vi&#xA;- `Ctrl + j` or `Enter` to copy the selected text to the clipboard.&#xA;&#xA;This is default, and again can be over-written by using the following config:&#xA;&#xA;```&#xA;setw -g mode-keys vi&#xA;&#xA;bind-key -T copy-mode-vi &lt;your-key&gt; send-keys -X copy-pipe-and-cancel&#xA;&#xA;# Example: Remap &#39;y&#39; in copy-mode-vi to copy selection and exit&#xA;# bind-key -T copy-mode-vi y send-keys -X copy-pipe-and-cancel&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;This all would be applied to copy-mode if you are not changing the keybindings for copy-mode-vi.&#xA;&#xA;That&#39;s it this should be more than enough for most of the log-driven or printf debugging tasks.&#xA;</content>
      <type>til</type>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>