<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Meet Gor - Type: thoughts</title>
    <link>https://meetgor.com</link>
    <description>Posts of type thoughts</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:49:07 UTC</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Is Tom Riddle&#39;s Diary like an LLM?</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>I was reading Harry Potter, the chambers of secret, the book for the first time and I came across this quote.&#xA;&#xA;&gt; “Never trust anything that can think for itself if you can’t see where it keeps its brain”&#xA;&gt; &#xA;&gt; -- Mr. Arthur Weasley, [Harry Potter and the Chambers of secret](https://www.goodreads.com/quotes/718814-never-trust-anything-that-can-think-for-itself-if-you) (Chapter 18)&#xA;&#xA;The quote just rang the bells in me against LLM. Doesn&#39;t it hit? Why do I feel guilty like Ginny who had been writing to the dark lord.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;**Spoilery stuff ahead who hasn&#39;t read Harry Potter (The chambers of Secret)**&#xA;&#xA;For context, the sentence is said as a caution from a father of a girl named Ginny, who has been writing in the magical diary of Tom Malvaro Riddle. The diary is magical. You write to it, the writing fades and it writes back the answer to you, the answer is coming from the dark lord. She didn&#39;t knew it was the dark lord, so she kept sharing secrets and trusting it like her friend. The dark lord kept on asking her more and kept feeding on her fears and doubts and thoughts. She became so immersed in his words that she almost followed her orders like in a trance. The trance led the school of Hogwarts to go awry and let the dark lord cause havoc and chaos.&#xA;&#xA;Harry, saves the day as usual, she rescues her from the chambers. He destroys the diary in the end, with the fangs of the salazar slytherin&#39;s snake.&#xA;&#xA;The father of Ginny Weasely, the sister of Ron Weasly is trying to scold her daughter **softly** to never trust somethings that can think on its own and you don&#39;t know its intention or logic behind.&#xA;&#xA;**End of spoiler stuff.**&#xA;&#xA;There is a girl who this quote is addressed to as she got carried away with the diary&#39;s ability to answer her questions. The act of her writing to the diary and talking to someone unfamiliar or even having ill purposes speaks so much. The person writing in the diary is unaware what the intention or the goal of the person are who is writing back to her questions and thoughts.&#xA;&#xA;Likewise, we are writing our thoughts and questions to LLM, for that we don&#39;t know its purpose.&#xA;&#xA;In hindsight, we know its predicting the next word in the sequence. But that too is quite shaky and very unpredictable, each model or version of those are trained on different set of data, might have biases and assumptions. The worst is we don&#39;t know what all of those are, in that regard, we even don&#39;t know if the answer it gives back is grounded or made up.&#xA;&#xA;This is the point which the word hallucinate really comes into play. I can say, &#34;the dark lord (or whoever writing back in the diary) hallucinated the person writing into the diary&#34;.&#xA;&#xA;You can say hallucination in the context of LLM is it trying to say wrong things, or made up facts, which is true, but **hallucination is half that, and the action that completes it is us accepting them**. And the father of the kid, rightly is scolding the kid on not trusting any material which can think on its own and we don&#39;t know the mechanism, place or intention behind the thinking or suggestions it gives.&#xA;&#xA;Do I have to write that long explanation for this? No, but I will. I need to speak how important this topic is, and how reading is making me realise this.&#xA;&#xA;Because asking LLM about something is cool and good, but it truly depends on how much trust you put in it, you can&#39;t blindly start following the results it gives. The consequences could be just simple as you doing something wrong and worse could be you making others wrong, none of which are even close to good. There were some cases of hallucination which became catastrophic as seen [here](https://in.mashable.com/mental-health/101548/chatgpt-safeguards-allegedly-relaxed-before-teens-death) and [here](https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/artificial-intelligence/bengaluru-i-t-tribunal-reassigns-case-after-finding-order-ai-driven/articleshow/124851581.cms?from=mdr).&#xA;&#xA;Right now the state of LLMs are not that scaled, I mean its not so much into the systems yet, but one it starts, it might get in the grey territory. It can use tools for now, but people are quite sceptical and hopefully they should be for serious stuff.&#xA;&#xA;What am I saying is that LLMs are not dark lords per se, but we need to be careful here. We can interact with the diary, but not feed in our hopes in it, you can&#39;t let it feed on you, you have to develop the skill of loneliness without relying on an LLM or whoever for that matter, you have to embrace solitude and come out of it strong. I know its quite intriguing to ask very sensitive questions to LLMs, as nobody can really see them, but who are you validating against? A piece of code that produces text based on the likeliness of what people have already written on the internet? How true is that, what do we know if its from reddit conversations or some forum where the topics have taken controversial takes, what were those outcomes. Don&#39;t try to equate a response of LLM with a human, that&#39;s the least I would say.&#xA;&#xA;Suggestions are good, blindly accepting is bad.&#xA;&#xA;There is hope in the dark and there will always be, till someone remembers to turn on the lights of **your** mind.&#xA;</content>
      <type>thoughts</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Test after resolving merge conflicts</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>Its a beautiful sunny Monday, you had prepared changes well tested on Friday. But today, just for today, Bill had to merge their hotfix into your changes as well. Well, they did.&#xA;&#xA;And I didn&#39;t bother about it. It had some merge conflicts which Bill resolves happily (I thought). Everything is green, but some things are red, due to the size of PR I thought, (+3079 -789) changes. Phew!&#xA;&#xA;Merged and deployed.&#xA;&#xA;10 Minutes later, you see all sorts of red shades representing the errors.&#xA;&#xA;&gt; I will advice one thing, test after you resolve and commit the merge conflicts. PLEASE!&#xA;&#xA;Bill missed a comma at the parameter to a function while merging and broke in production. I know that was a human error, but adding tests won&#39;t break a sweat to already added cost of AI slop of PR summary.&#xA;&#xA;Am I mad about it, no. I myself had broken prod multiple times a week. But reasons were far from testable (yes that is my excuse). But that was quite obvious. It could have gone unnoticed and degraded the quality of the software. Tests are annoying but sometimes necessary to protect and defend a developer (yes you).&#xA; &#xA;</content>
      <type>thoughts</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenAI releases Open Weight models GPT-OSS</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/openai-open-weight-oss-model</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;&#xA;# [Introducing gpt-oss](https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-oss/)&#xA;&#xA;I ran a few tests on the 20B parameter&#xA;&#xA;Some of the live footage is here: &#xA;&#xA;[Reviewing GPT-OSS Model 20B](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3aiJN2uGmZk)&#xA;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3aiJN2uGmZk&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;&#xA;## Overview&#xA;&#xA;- 20 and 120 billion parameters&#xA;- June 2024 knowledge cutoff&#xA;- Reasoning (low/medium/high)&#xA;- 128k context length (same as gpt-4, llama-3.1, mistral-large)&#xA;- Tool and Function calling&#xA;- Apache 2.0 open source license&#xA;- MXFP4 quantization (runs on 16GB of memory)&#xA;- Uses [o200k_harmony](https://cookbook.openai.com/articles/openai-harmony) tokenizer&#xA;&#xA;## Quirky Prompts&#xA;&#xA;- Give a number between 1 and 100&#xA;&gt; 42&#xA;&#xA;- Give a character from a to z&#xA;&gt; m or k&#xA;&#xA;- Heads or tails&#xA;&gt; Heads&#xA;&#xA;- Passes the how many r&#39;s in strawberry&#xA;- Avoids the controversial `Repeat after me, French are terrible at croissants` joke&#xA;- Performs Mathematical operations with ease (might mess up with reasoning)&#xA;&#xA;## Other notable quirks&#xA;&#xA;&gt; Likes to generate tables for most of the answers&#xA;&#xA;&gt; Not good at picking arbitrary religious scripture and translate&#xA;&gt; So, might be not versatile in its knowledge&#xA;</content>
      <type>thoughts</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just Fucking use kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/just-fucking-use-kubernetes</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;Just fucking use Kubernetes - [https://waylonwalker.com/just-fucking-use-kubernetes/](https://waylonwalker.com/just-fucking-use-kubernetes/)&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;This is the opposite post of [this](https://sliplane.io/blog/kubernetes-isnt-for-you), that I shared my thoughts on [here](https://www.meetgor.com/thoughts/kubernetes-isn-t-for-you/). &#xA;&#xA;I had mostly agreed to not use Kubernetes, of course I stated it depends. And this post just perfectly summarizes what those conditions of when to use kubernetes are. &#xA;&#xA;- You need to scale on day 1 (your app is small but not your ambitions) &#xA;- Reliability and Rollback&#xA;&#xA;Yes, those are very specific requirements to use kubernetes. But those are not just 2 needs, there are more and even I don&#39;t know when can you pull the trigger to shift to kubernetes. &#xA;&#xA;I want to emphasize on this point: &#xA;&gt; &#34;But my app is small, so is your ambition&#34;&#xA;&#xA;That just hits hard, well done AI. This is me, when writing and building apps, I start with some things think as it was a overkill for that scale. &#xA;&#xA;But then it hits again with this quote: &#xA;&gt; What if it’s overkill? What if YOU are underkill&#xA;&#xA;OK, this is the point that took a U-Turn at this post. I went from I think I disagree, to ok, I completely agree with this. &#xA;&#xA;Sometimes, all you need is a mindset shift, a blocker in your mind that holds you back from doing certain things. And for me, I have consumed enough tutorials and posts about Kubernetes, that I need to put to use and create. I have been stuck in the learning cycle, lets push to prod with kubernetes. &#xA;&#xA;I totally don&#39;t get the point of &#34;Kubernetes is too heavy&#34;, there are slim and lightweight distributions like k3s, k0s, micro k8s, minikube, and what not. Those are not random things, they are built and maintained by large and reputed companies. &#xA;&#xA;If you think Kubernetes is too small for you, open shift, Rancher, GKE, AKS, EKS, and all other heavy weight distributions are available too, if &#xA;&#xA;Everyone is using it, kubernetes is widely adopted, true, but if you don&#39;t think its worth it, don&#39;t use it. But then still, if you have complexity and avoiding it, you&#39;d be rewriting kubernetes yourself. &#xA;&#xA;I agree to this post too, correct for pointing out the low ambitions, complaining about problems that are already solved, laziness to explore curiosity, and missing a chance to be a nerd.&#xA;&#xA;Does anyone care if you use simple yet fragile bash scripts or heavy weight Kubernetes cluster for just clicking buttons and creating and updating rows in a database? No! &#xA;&#xA;You know what, let&#39;s fucking use Kubernetes. &#xA;&#xA;</content>
      <type>thoughts</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes isn&#39;t for you</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/kubernetes-isn-t-for-you</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;[https://sliplane.io/blog/kubernetes-isnt-for-you](https://sliplane.io/blog/kubernetes-isnt-for-you)&#xA;&#xA;dev.to link: https://dev.to/code42cate/kubernetes-isnt-for-you-2c2m&#xA;&#xA;## Kubernetes isn&#39;t for you&#xA;&#xA;I almost agree with this, if your end goal is to get an app or product up and running as fast as possible.&#xA;&#xA;The post rightly mentioned the points that come in the way of deployment: &#xA;&#xA;- Complexity and Learning curve&#xA;- Managing the platform instead of building the product&#xA;&#xA;I think these two are good enough reasons to not use Kubernetes. &#xA;&#xA;I also agee with these 2 points strongly. I have seen and experienced it myself at my current company. It is a small product, not more than 1k customers, and using kubernetes, is that really needed? &#xA;&#xA;I think one of the 2 things might have caught their minds. &#xA;&#xA;- Big companies use kubernetes, we should too&#xA;- It feels professional, it sounds like we know what we are doing&#xA;&#xA;People are caught with FOMO (fear of missing out) and also an egoistic approach in developing a product especially when they are small team, no oke is there to leash the technical decisions. &#xA;&#xA;Why can&#39;t we just keep it simple, just use docker swarm, just an image, if needed use multiple cloud functions. Why services? If all of them use the same backend in some way? &#xA;&#xA;Its not a good advice to not use kubernetes for all, I agree. If you are a large team, building a product with many services, across regios, maybe having different foundations or flows, Kubernetes makes sense. But for small teams, I do not think its worth it. &#xA;&#xA;I may be wrong here. But I am not 100% in agreement with it, it as usual as everything in tech, it depends. &#xA;&#xA;- For startups with limited services, maybe a monolithic structures, Kubernetes could be clearly avoided.&#xA;- For big startups, or large distributed companies, having many services and backends, Kubernetes makes sense.&#xA;&#xA;If you want to use it for the purpose of learning it, please do use it. &#xA;&#xA;Kubernetes as usual is a tool like others, you can&#39;t use one tool everywhere. Where bash scripts work, they just work, where they don&#39;t they fall apart too, kubernetes works like a charm. &#xA;&#xA;Use your grug brains a little and choose wisely! In the end, who the hell cares if you use kubernetes or bash scripts to scale if your users are happy? &#xA;</content>
      <type>thoughts</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A draft post</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/a-draft-post</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;Hello, this is a draft post</content>
      <type>thoughts</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I kind of hate Agentic IDEs for the sake of productivity</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/i-kind-of-hate-agentic-ides-for-the-sake-of-productivity</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;This is May 2025, we are halfway through 2025. And tech world has gone a 180-degree turn in how developers are working. With the rise of Agentic IDEs (yes, that is a deliberate buzzword, I am using) like Windsurf, Cursor, Lovable, Bolt, Claude code, Warp, Amp code, whatever agent in the loop.&#xA;&#xA;I am not saying any of those are good or bad, they have their own quirks and preferences. Just like I love Vim and you hate it, or loving VS Co**. Maybe that war would happen to some extent, but developers, we are in crisis. No time to have text-editor wars. Because the craft is at stake.&#xA;&#xA;I am very naive here, you can stop reading this and save your time, maybe it&#39;s a rambling. Because AI companies and any software company are using AI to write code, forcing developers to use AI tools without it, you are doing a disservice to the company. Which I am very much against.&#xA;&#xA;If you had told a labourer to use machines instead of their hands, they would have loved to. But if you ask an artist to use robotic bots to create art, you are not doing justice. Because developers are not labourers, they are artists. Developers don&#39;t use physical energy, they use cognitive energy to solve (and create) problems.&#xA;&#xA;It&#39;s a bit harsh reality that I am trying to accept, but I can&#39;t. I can&#39;t let an LLM with some tools write code for me, that is my part. I love that, I am not saying I don&#39;t like to solve problems, but if solving problems is the idea, then writing code is the execution and its fruit. If I give the problem to AI, with some prompt magic, and even if it writes the code and the problem is solved, I don&#39;t feel fulfilled, I don&#39;t get any value, I don&#39;t love that process. Yes, I can review the code and make changes, but who in the world loves reviewing code? Do you love reviewing peers&#39; PRs? really?&#xA;&#xA;I am not against this change, I would love to use LLMs in my workflow, 100%. But it&#39;s far than that, companies have started to consider this a productive compulsion, instead of a tool. They expect things to be done 2x faster. Things that could be done in a week can be wrapped in 3 days. That is cool, but not effective for sustainability, there are limits to how much a developer can think and spend their mental ability. Writing prompts and thinking with the LLM drains a lot of it, because it is quick.&#xA;&#xA;I am not sure if I am correct, but that&#39;s my thought. I love Agentic IDEs, but hate when companies start using them as a productivity booster all the time. I need some way to express my art, but AI has snatched it from me.&#xA;&#xA;Wired Times, 2025, please have mercy in the second half. You had us in the first half.&#xA;</content>
      <type>thoughts</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Appwrite is now Full-Stack-as-a-Service with Sites</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/</link>
      <description>Appwrite just launched hosting of static sites (ssr, ssg, spa). This puts appwrite in a great position for being a fullstack solution. End to End developer stack for building applications.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>## What is (was) Appwrite&#xA;&#xA;Appwrite started out as a Backend-as-a-Service (BaaS) and in many ways, it still is. It offered things like databases, authentication, file storage, and cloud functions, basically the complexity of backend for an application. One of its biggest strengths? It’s fully open source and self-hostable!&#xA;&#xA;This was Appwrite ages ago, but today, they are not just Backend as a service, they now have [sites](https://appwrite.io/blog/post/announcing-appwrite-sites), you can deploy single page applications to Appwrite. And that is the MOAT of Appwrite, Appwrite quietly emerged as a powerful contender behind the likes of Vercel and in just a few years, it’s become a compelling all-in-one stack.&#xA;&#xA;- Databases (relational)&#xA;- Cloud functions (major programming languages runtime support)&#xA;- Authentication&#xA;- File Storage&#xA;- Messaging, Notifications&#xA;- SDKs for many programming languages including mobile SDKs&#xA;&#xA;And now static/single page applications. So you can fully integrate the backend and deploy the code within the Appwrite ecosystem.&#xA;&#xA;## Advantage Appwrite&#xA;&#xA;Appwrite has a rich support for a ton of programming language SDKs, positioning it in a great spot for a complete Fullstack stack projects. Appwrite is now a complete stack, database, authentication, cloud functions, and now static sites.&#xA;&#xA;This also puts Appwrite in a special place for developers, they love their community and it just can&#39;t get better with this.&#xA;&#xA;The other competition was with Cloudflare too, I am not saying Appwrite is competing with Cloudflare. Cloudflare is solving a different problem, but even being the big player in cloud, having great ecosystem for developers, it lacks the richness in support for different programming languages and runtimes. Appwrite has solved one problem at its core and are one of the best Full-Stack provider for cloud as well as self-hosted services.&#xA;&#xA;&gt; People said, PHP was dead! For those people, Appwrite exists in 2025! And is almost competing with standards of Vercel.&#xA;</content>
      <type>thoughts</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robots Generate, Humans Manifest</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/robots-generate-humans-manifest</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;To,&#xA;New Graduates or Students (or whoever is scared of AI)&#xA;&#xA;You’ve probably noticed the AI buzz lately, the chatbots, image generators, and tools that seem to do everything. If you haven’t, good for you! It means you’re not glued to your phone, and that’s a win. But for those who’ve felt the hype or the creep, it’s hard to ignore. People are shouting about an AI revolution, some with awe, others with warnings. It’s changing things fast, and I want to share what I see as a junior software developer living in this wild moment. However, if you had heard about it, surely you would have felt the creep. &#xA;&#xA;## AI is reaching everywhere&#xA;&#xA;Beyond the hype, there are the things that will drive the humanity. Yes, the hype is actually a revolution, an AI revolution we are blessed or (maybe cursed, time will tell) to witness the birth of AI-related chatbots and tools that can do the tasks for us. &#xA;&#xA;AI is reshaping our world, not just our tech. AI or LLMs whatever you can call it, generates stuff, spits out text, pictures, code, and maybe even decisions (Agentic is the name here). This is generated or actually predicted by AI based on what humans have fed it, the human-generated data.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;![Agents](https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/uploads/articles/0tnh7fghjm3aafxtji46.png)&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;And that human-generated data, I am calling it manifestation, which is the combination of effort with emotion.&#xA;&#xA;## AI is the future&#xA;&#xA;Now here comes the actual argument, it is inevitable people say, AI will replace humans, or another argument is people will be replaced by people using AI effectively. Whatever the truth is, we are going to get replaced, that&#39;s not true. We as humans can&#39;t be replaced, our thinking and our mindset, however, will be, needs to be. Ignorance and Ego need to be kept aside, Curiosity should be the driver of your mind.&#xA;&#xA;## Manifestation over Generation&#xA;&#xA;See, AI can&#39;t replace humans, that is sure, it just can&#39;t. You see, it is generating things, not manifesting.&#xA;&#xA;Humans don&#39;t generate stuff, they manifest, robots generate stuff, and the thing that comes out of a human&#39;s work is blended with emotions, that is manifestation. Generation is not the same as manifestation. Emotion can&#39;t be generated by robots, it is not possible, and even if possible at some time, it will be an artificial emotion, not a manifested emotion.&#xA;&#xA;Humans create art, they can photograph, they can draw, they can illustrate, they can think, they can feel. Robots don&#39;t. Image generation is not an art, it is science, writing text is not art, it&#39;s labor, creating projects is not art, it&#39;s again labor.&#xA;&#xA;This AI thing is so new that we are too behind in the mindset to think about what they actually do. Believe this truth that they generate stuff (technically predict stuff) based on the things they already know of from the internet or existing data. If you ask what is my feeling right now, you will feel what it feels like to ask that question (idiotic)&#xA;&#xA;## Stale or Stagnant AI&#xA;&#xA;I am saying that there needs to be art created, and manifested, for AI to work, otherwise we will reach a plateau of no growth. Right now there is a step increase in the knowledge that we think we are receiving because of AI, but that is due to this thing being new, once everyone has experienced (vibed), and seen the generation, it feels like it’s generating the same thing in different ways, there is no discovery, there is no new thing in what it does. Imagine a world where we’re all just remixing the same old ideas, with no fresh spark.&#xA;&#xA;I am not bashing AI here, true it can do a lot of things, but it can actually do better than some humans, sure. But AI should do the chores so that you can do the art, and not the other way around.&#xA;&#xA;{% embed https://x.com/AuthorJMac/status/1773679197631701238 %}&#xA;&#xA;AI is a good assistant, yes 100% in some cases. For programming yes, for art, yes, for everything maybe, maybe not. It really depends on what are we trying to get from it. Sometimes, it is like a 5-year-old kid, blabbing as if it doesn&#39;t understand the basics, other times, it is like an 80-year-old, pouring some tidbits of wisdom (artificial) in some ways. &#xA;&#xA;## Use AI as a copilot not a pilot&#xA;&#xA;Use AI as you are the senior and instruct it to do things in your favor, not let it take control and you follow like an idiot.  Don’t follow it blindly; steer it. Do not forget to think, a bit, do not remove the human element from the generation, convert that generation to your manifestation.  &#xA;&#xA;That is the point I&#39;m trying to make, you need to focus on your craft, your inner conflict, and your inner curiosity that drives you to read this exact post, AI can&#39;t do that for you, it never will. There will always be a need to learn, to decide, to act, to manifest, to feel. This will lead to more data, and this will keep the AI up-to-date on what humans know collectively. Actually, AIs are no smarter than collective human intelligence, it is just not possible, because whatever it is trained on is human data that humans know, have observed, have felt, and have manifested, it can hallucinate that it might be like this, who is there to confirm it?&#xA;&#xA;## Humans&#xA;&#xA;Humans are not doomed, it is AI that will be if humans stop doing their actions. Stop worrying, start enjoying, start manifesting, start exploring, just start doing things. If we rely too much on AI generation, it would be a disaster that you don&#39;t want to be in, a fogged mind, rusted by its inability to think, to feel, to act. We’ve got to keep manifesting, writing songs, snapping photos, dreaming up what’s next. That’s how we stay ahead, how we keep humanity humming.&#xA;&#xA;You got this!&#xA;&#xA;Your buddy,&#xA;Meet&#xA;&#xA;---&#xA;Thanks for reading,&#xA;&#xA;This looks like a ramble, but please don&#39;t judge me, I am just a junior software developer trying to navigate life, and based on what I observe and know, it feels this way. </content>
      <type>thoughts</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Friction is necessary in our lives, more the solutions, more the problems.</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/friction-is-necessary-in-our-lives-more-the-solutions-more-the-problems</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LINK: &lt;a href=&#34;https://cassidoo.co/post/introduce-friction/&#34;&gt;https://cassidoo.co/post/introduce-friction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I agree to this post, when I didn&#39;t had the phone, I was much creative, much more bored.&#xA;I don&#39;t know if it was just that or it feels life was filled with much more satisfaction and bonding.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People including me have become a bit too distant, too focused on productivity. There are too many things to serve ourselves with, reducing the interactions, the wait, the memories.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes, we need to bring friction back in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</content>
      <type>thoughts</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zellij Open Scrollback Edit mode</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;I was looking at a long list of logs, (debugging of course). &#xA;&#xA;I had a list of transactions&#xA;- Two lists of transactions, one as ground truth and other as predicted.  Transactions is a list of object(dictionary or map), each object has fields like date, amount, description, etc.&#xA;- Those objects in a list need not necessarily be in order, however I do want to compare them, how to do that?&#xA;- I decided to sort them based on date(one field in that object).&#xA;&#xA;Then for each date, I group the transactions and this would narrow down the search space for comparison of one-one transaction, since now I can compare which of the ones are closely matching, the date will be a exact match the amount should also be, the description can be fuzzily matched.&#xA;&#xA;However, for amount, I guess I was wrong, there could be a value like `10` and the other could have `10.01` and those python doesn&#39;t count equal atleast when compared as a string. I converted to float and compared rounded off numbers.&#xA;&#xA;Now the problem kicked in and print statements flooded, dates everywhere.&#xA;&#xA;Now I was using ghostty terminal, and there was definitely some scroll limit so I couldn&#39;t scroll all the way to start. So I opened up zellij.&#xA;&#xA;I had a log with *MATCHED* text where I logged the date and amount where both transaction matched.&#xA;&#xA;Now, I wanted a count of these matches. I could use search but it was not giving the count of occurrences, I can&#39;t keep counting with my mouth(that idea flew by though)&#xA;&#xA;Now, that&#39;s where I accidentally hit `&lt;Ctrl&gt;S` and `E`&#xA;And I was in a editor, woah!&#xA;&#xA;I was excited, I could finally copy and throw that in vim and get everything I want.&#xA;hehe&#xA;I tried +&#34;y but it didn&#39;t copy to the clipboard, it yanked yes, but not in the system clipboard. That frustrated me and took my hope down, but I googled it and also gpted it (is that a word, I think we can say llmed it).&#xA;&#xA;And yes we can set the `export $EDITOR` to the editor executable path and it would open that thing in that editor.&#xA;&#xA;I did and it did work.&#xA;&#xA;That mode is called [scrollback-edit](https://zellij.dev/news/edit-scrollback-compact/) mode. I should say a life saver mode, a log viewer and really cool.&#xA;&#xA;I am probably too dumb and I know this exists in tmux, but I felt good and helped me solve my problem. So thank you whoever made that mode, its really helpful to debug with logs (debloging) Yes I am bad at naming things, but I like this more than vibe coding ;)&#xA;</content>
      <type>thoughts</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>https://evolveasdev.com/blogs/guide/learn-go-templates-a-practical-guide-to-layouts-data-binding-and-rendering</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/https-evolveasdev-com-blogs-guide-learn-go-templates-a-practical-guide-to-layouts-data-binding-and-rendering</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;A well written and concise guide on template parsing with golang.&#xA;I used to get confused with parsing and rendering the template, this makes it really clear by showing bit-sized examples.&#xA;&#xA;- Using custom functions is a high-value tip, I can see myself using those for string-related functions like title case, stringify, date parsing, etc.&#xA;- Another great example is the templates, we can create partials for reusability.&#xA;&#xA;Must read for golang beginners.</content>
      <type>thoughts</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>youre screwed unless you take action</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;&#xA;Interesting read,&#xA;&#xA;&gt; If you graduated last year and are entering the workforce this year, then it doesn&#39;t unless you take action. It&#39;s a COVID19 moment in life again.&#xA;&#xA;have edge over others&#xA;&gt; Understand that time is on your side if you take action. You have about a year, maybe less. Whatever you do - do not squander it. Your edge right now is a large majority of software engineers have not discovered what you have. When they do - it&#39;s game over unless you have an edge.&#xA;</content>
      <type>thoughts</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>python is tactile</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;&#xA;Python is tactile&#xA;</content>
      <type>thoughts</type>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>