<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Meet Gor - Tag: git</title>
    <link>https://meetgor.com</link>
    <description>Posts tagged with git</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:49:07 UTC</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Add hunks: only line specific changes with git add -p</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;I had made the changes for a future release, next set of changes so to speak in git terms. Then, I encountered a bug while testing the previous changes. Now, I could have &#xA;1. Open VS Code and add that little `+` icon in the gutter to fix the bug&#xA;2. Create a separate branch with stashed changes for this new feature&#xA;3. Use GitSigns in NeoVim&#xA;4. Use `git add -p` to stage [hunks](https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Git-Tools-Interactive-Staging)&#xA;&#xA;The last one was a gem given by ChatGPT, and then I went a bit rabbit hole for reading about it and it turns out it&#39;s real! &#xA;&#xA;It&#39;s called staging patches, and it has an interactive mode to select or reject each hunk (patch, line of changes) at a time. So by entering the command `git add -p` this will let you go through each file and individual change (patch/hunk) and take action interactively. You can use the below commands for moving one hunk or patch at a time: &#xA;- `y` for adding (staging) the current hunk (patch)&#xA;- `n` for not staging the current hunk&#xA;&#xA;Or you can even use the below commands for moving one file at once:&#xA;- `a` for adding (staging) all the patches in the file (just like `git add file.txt`)&#xA;- `d` for not staging the file at all, just skip the file for patching&#xA;&#xA;If there are multiple hunks (patches) in the file, the prompt will show the other options like `[y,n,q,a,d,j,J,g,/,e,?]` &#xA;&#xA;```&#xA;(1/7) Stage this hunk [y,n,q,a,d,j,J,g,/,e,?]? g&#xA;1: -33,6 +33,7 +from app.utils.utils import get_additional_param&#xA;2: -345,6 +346,7 + strict_check = str_to_bool(get_additional_param(&#34;stri&#xA;....&#xA;....&#xA;7: -875,7 +878,7 - if strict_check:&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;This shows the `g`, `j`, `J`, `/`, and `e` which are quite helpful for navigating across multiple patches (hunks) in the file. I haven&#39;t explored all of them, but the 4, I showed earlier, are the ones that I think I will be using extensively now, within the terminal. No need of fancy editor shenanigans and redundant branching tricks. &#xA;&#xA;Git Good!&#xA;</content>
      <type>til</type>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>