<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Meet Gor - Type: til</title>
    <link>https://meetgor.com</link>
    <description>Posts of type til</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:49:08 UTC</pubDate>
    <item>
      <title>Tmux scroll mode select and copy</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;I have found scrolling in tmux is a bit unconventional. Maybe its just me, but sometimes, the terminal interfaces are different, sometimes they are a bit wired, I use Ghostty right now, so selection without tmux works a charm, but the moment I am in tmux, ahmm, it kind of breaks.&#xA;&#xA;The selection of text doesn&#39;t work with the mouse atleast, so I thought, I need a keyboard centric selection and copying mechanism, and dug in this rabit hole. Turns out, tmux is way better in selection then zellij, the multiplexer I had been using due to scroll and selection issues in terminal interfaces.&#xA;&#xA;It&#39;s simple as `Prefix + [` to enter the scroll mode, `Shift+V` or `Ctrl+space` or `Ctrl+v` to start the selection in different ways, and finally, `Enter` or `Ctrl+j` to copy to clipboard. There is a dedicated mode for vi users, to feel at home. Tmux + Vim again a deadly combo.&#xA;&#xA;## Entering Scroll Mode&#xA;&#xA;To enter scroll mode, I had this config setup in my `.tmux.conf` file:&#xA;&#xA;```&#xA;set -g mouse on&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;However if you want to enter without mouse on, you can use:&#xA;&#xA;```&#xA;Ctrl + b + [&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;Here the `Ctrl + b` is for the prefix key, and `[` is the key for enterring into the  `Scroll Mode`&#xA;&#xA;From here on you can use `hjkl` or arrow keys to scroll up or down.&#xA;&#xA;To quit, you can press `q` or hit escape.&#xA;&#xA;## Selecting &#xA;&#xA;Right now in scrolling mode, you can only navigate to the next or previous line. &#xA;&#xA;But you can use `Ctrl + &lt;Space&gt;` to select any arbitrary sections of the terminal output.&#xA;There are two modes in tmux for this the `copy-mode` i.e. the default, and the `copy-mode-vi`.&#xA;&#xA;Without any config, this is be set to the default `copy-mode`, so we can use `Ctrl + Space` to begin selection in the scroll mode.&#xA;&#xA;To get more keybindings for the copy-mode and copy-mode-vi, use &#xA;&#xA;For copy-mode&#xA;```&#xA;tmux list-keys -T copy-mode&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;For copy-mode-vi&#xA;```&#xA;tmux list-keys -T copy-mode-vi&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;This is a default and can be over-written by using the following config:&#xA;&#xA;```&#xA;setw -g mode-keys vi&#xA;unbind-key -T copy-mode-vi Space&#xA;&#xA;# replace &lt;your-key&gt; with the key combination you want&#xA;bind-key -T copy-mode-vi &lt;your-key&gt; send-keys -X begin-selection&#xA;&#xA;# Example: using ctrl + b + v as the key to start selection&#xA;# bind-key -T copy-mode-vi v send-keys -X begin-selection&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;This all would be applied to copy-mode if you are not changing the keybindings for copy-mode-vi.&#xA;&#xA;## Copying&#xA;&#xA;Once, you have the selected region or piece of text, you can copy that to the clipboard (that is what you do, while logs-driven debugging :).&#xA;&#xA;By default, you can use:&#xA;&#xA;For copy-mode&#xA;- `Ctrl + w` &#xA;&#xA;or &#xA;&#xA;For copy-mode-vi&#xA;- `Ctrl + j` or `Enter` to copy the selected text to the clipboard.&#xA;&#xA;This is default, and again can be over-written by using the following config:&#xA;&#xA;```&#xA;setw -g mode-keys vi&#xA;&#xA;bind-key -T copy-mode-vi &lt;your-key&gt; send-keys -X copy-pipe-and-cancel&#xA;&#xA;# Example: Remap &#39;y&#39; in copy-mode-vi to copy selection and exit&#xA;# bind-key -T copy-mode-vi y send-keys -X copy-pipe-and-cancel&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;This all would be applied to copy-mode if you are not changing the keybindings for copy-mode-vi.&#xA;&#xA;That&#39;s it this should be more than enough for most of the log-driven or printf debugging tasks.&#xA;</content>
      <type>til</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Python version in a UV project</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/getting-python-version-in-a-uv-project</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;I was live streaming, creating a AI Coding Agent from scratch in Python. I was excited to create the agent. You can watch the [livestream](https://youtube.com/clip/Ugkx2AcRqaYcMgAqZgtA2k48iYb8sJf9VL6F?si=XTtC2zFs2Kloia0L) here. &#xA;&#xA;Anyways, the thing is the uv python project has a `. python_version` file that will store the python version.&#xA;&#xA;I thought, it might be used from `pyproject.toml`, or other setup files. But that is really neat from uv.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;</content>
      <type>til</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Add hunks: only line specific changes with git add -p</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;I had made the changes for a future release, next set of changes so to speak in git terms. Then, I encountered a bug while testing the previous changes. Now, I could have &#xA;1. Open VS Code and add that little `+` icon in the gutter to fix the bug&#xA;2. Create a separate branch with stashed changes for this new feature&#xA;3. Use GitSigns in NeoVim&#xA;4. Use `git add -p` to stage [hunks](https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Git-Tools-Interactive-Staging)&#xA;&#xA;The last one was a gem given by ChatGPT, and then I went a bit rabbit hole for reading about it and it turns out it&#39;s real! &#xA;&#xA;It&#39;s called staging patches, and it has an interactive mode to select or reject each hunk (patch, line of changes) at a time. So by entering the command `git add -p` this will let you go through each file and individual change (patch/hunk) and take action interactively. You can use the below commands for moving one hunk or patch at a time: &#xA;- `y` for adding (staging) the current hunk (patch)&#xA;- `n` for not staging the current hunk&#xA;&#xA;Or you can even use the below commands for moving one file at once:&#xA;- `a` for adding (staging) all the patches in the file (just like `git add file.txt`)&#xA;- `d` for not staging the file at all, just skip the file for patching&#xA;&#xA;If there are multiple hunks (patches) in the file, the prompt will show the other options like `[y,n,q,a,d,j,J,g,/,e,?]` &#xA;&#xA;```&#xA;(1/7) Stage this hunk [y,n,q,a,d,j,J,g,/,e,?]? g&#xA;1: -33,6 +33,7 +from app.utils.utils import get_additional_param&#xA;2: -345,6 +346,7 + strict_check = str_to_bool(get_additional_param(&#34;stri&#xA;....&#xA;....&#xA;7: -875,7 +878,7 - if strict_check:&#xA;```&#xA;&#xA;This shows the `g`, `j`, `J`, `/`, and `e` which are quite helpful for navigating across multiple patches (hunks) in the file. I haven&#39;t explored all of them, but the 4, I showed earlier, are the ones that I think I will be using extensively now, within the terminal. No need of fancy editor shenanigans and redundant branching tricks. &#xA;&#xA;Git Good!&#xA;</content>
      <type>til</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zellij Open Scrollback Edit mode</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/zellij-open-scrollback-edit-mode</link>
      <description></description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2025 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;I was looking at a long list of logs, (debugging of course). &#xA;&#xA;I had a list of transactions&#xA;- Two list of transactions, one as ground truth and other as predicted.  Transactions is a list of object(dictionary or map), each object has fields like date, amount, description, etc.&#xA;- Those objects in a list need not necessarily be in order, however I do want to compare them, how to do that?&#xA;- I decided to sort them based on date(one field in that object).&#xA;&#xA;Then for each date, I group the transactions and this would narrow down the search space for comparison of one-one transaction, since now I can compare which of the ones are closely matching, the date will be a exact match the amount should also be, the description can be fuzzily matched.&#xA;&#xA;However, for amount, I guess I was wrong, there could be a value like `10` and the other could have `10.01` and those python doesn&#39;t count equal atleast when compared as a string. I converted to float and compared rounded off numbers.&#xA;&#xA;Now the problem kicked in and print statements flooded, dates everywhere.&#xA;&#xA;Now I was using ghostty terminal, and there was definitely some scroll limit so I couldn&#39;t scroll all the way to start. So I opened up zellij.&#xA;&#xA;I had a log with *MATCHED* text where I logged the date and amount where both transaction matched.&#xA;&#xA;Now, I wanted a count of these matches. I could use search but it was not giving the count of occurrences, I can&#39;t keep counting with my mouth(that idea flew by though)&#xA;&#xA;Now, that&#39;s where I accidentally hit `&lt;ctrl&gt;S` and `E`&#xA;And I was in a editor, woah!&#xA;&#xA;I was excited, I could finally copy and throw that in vim and get everything I want.&#xA;hehe&#xA;I tried +&#34;y but it didn&#39;t copy to the clipboard, it yanked yes, but not in the system clipboard. That frustrated me and took my hope down, but I googled it and also gpted it (is that a word, I think we can say llmed it).&#xA;&#xA;And yes we can set the `export $EDITOR` to the editor executable path and it would open that thing in that editor.&#xA;&#xA;I did and it did work.&#xA;&#xA;That mode is called [scrollback-edit](https://zellij.dev/news/edit-scrollback-compact/) mode. I should say a life saver mode, a log viewer and really cool.&#xA;&#xA;I am probably too dumb and I know this exists in tmux, but I felt good and helped me solve my problem. So thank you whoever made that mode, its really helpful to debug with logs (debloging) Yes I am bad at naming things, but I like this more than vibe coding ;)&#xA;</content>
      <type>til</type>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sample TIL</title>
      <link>https://meetgor.com/</link>
      <description>A sample TIL for ssg from scratch in golang</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <content>&#xA;## What I learned&#xA;&#xA;This is the content of the TIL&#xA;&#xA;## Conclusion&#xA;&#xA;Happy Coding :)&#xA;&#xA;</content>
      <type>til</type>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>